# Anirudhan J. Rajagopalan

linkedin.com/in/rajegannathan github.com/rajegannathan

#### Summary

Software Engineer with around 5 years of experience. Currently pursuing Masters in Computer Science at New York University. Skills include Full stack Web application development (python, java, ruby on rails, angularjs), Deep Learning (torch), and Machine Learning (python, numpy, sklearn). I am adept at researching and finding the right and simple way to build applications.

#### Education

#### Master of Science, Computer Science

Dec 2016

Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, New York University.

CGPA 3.75/4.0

Course List: Deep Learning, GPU — Architecture & Programming, Computational Machine Learning, Foundational Machine Learning, Web Search Engine, Realtime & Big data analysis.

### Bachelor of Technology, Information Technology

May 2010

Government College of Technology, Coimbatore

CGPA 8.01/10.0

## **Academic Projects**

2015 - 2016

Deep Learning (Torch)

- Improved classification accuracy on STL-10 by 2% using unsupervised learning methods. **Machine Learning** (python, numpy, scipy, HPC)
  - Used VLAD feature representation for classifying EEG signals for Grasp & Lift problem.
  - Classifying Liver & Kidney cancer using unbalanced protein expression data.%.

**Information Extraction** (Apache spark, Hive, python, java, lucene)

- Exploratory correlation analysis of NYC Taxi ridership and public events.
- Built a feature based reviews extractor for Amazon reviews. (java, python)

#### Work Experience

Around 5 years

#### Data Science Intern

Eyenuk Inc, Los Angeles, CA.

Jun 2016 — Aug 2016

- Explored the classification of Diabetic Retinopathy with **Residual Networks** against **VGG**.
- Setup a scalable production AWS deployment using VPC, Route 53, ELB, ACM, and RDS.

#### **Software Consultant**

Canvera Technologies, BGL, IN.

Jan 2014 — Sep 2014

- Performance Optimizations Load time:  $^{\sim}10 \text{ sec} \rightarrow 1 \text{ sec}$ . Asset size:  $^{\sim}1.5\text{Mb} \rightarrow ^{\sim}600\text{Kb}$ .
- Setup the application architecture & development process. Mentored the development team.

#### Founding Member

f1circle.com, HYD, IN.

May 2013 — Nov 2013

- Built the complete application from scratch. (ROR, Angularjs, Memcached, Redis)
- Built Information extraction engine. It extracts name, place, & price info from user's posts.

#### Freelancer

India.

May 2013 — Jan 2015

- Implemented the common sign-on page, branding workflows and modal framework for Vera.
- Built Urblotter (app.urblotter.com) a betting website for FIFA 2014. (ROR, Angularjs).

#### Software Enginneer

Insideview Inc, India

Oct 2011 — May 2013

- Developed in-product notification framework using **Drools framework** & **Lucene indexes**.
- Built the Activitystream security framework using AWS Simpledb and custom eventbus.

#### Software Engineer

United Online Inc, India

Jul 2010 — Sep 2011

• Built a RPC framework for spam filtering. Automated day-to-day tasks using Perl scripts.